I'll start by calculating the confidence interval of the effect size for
我会先计算效应值的置信区间
which I'll only need the total numbers.
这只需要总数
First, I'll calculate the estimated difference, which is the experiment
首先计算估计差值
click through rate minus the control click through rate and comes to 0.0116.
即实验组的点击率减去对照组 结果为 0.0116
Next, I'll need to calculate the standard error for
然后计算本项实验
the sample size we have.
样本量的标准误差
I can do this using the same method as before, assuming that the standard error
计算方法和前面一样
is proportional to the square root of 1 over n1 plus 1 over n2.
假设标准误差同 N1 分之一与 N2 分之一和的平方根成正比
This gives that the standard error for this experiment is 0.0026.
得出本实验的标准误差为 0.0026
To get the margin of error,
为得到误差范围
I'll multiply the standard error by the z score and I get 0.0051.
用 z 值 1.96 乘以标准误差 得到 0.0051
Then the confidence interval goes from 0.0065 to 0.0167.
置信区间则为 0.0065 至 0.0167
Since the confidence interval does not include zero,
由于置信区间不包括 0
these results are statistically significant.
实验结果具有统计显著性
That is, it's unlikely that there was no real difference.
也就是说 实验结果间确实存在差异
However, the confidence interval does include the practical significance
但是置信区间包括了实际显著性的最小值
boundary, meaning that I can't be confident at the 95% level that the size
这表明效应值落在置信区间的
of this effect is something that I care about.
几率不一定能达到 95%
Now to do the sign test, I'll need to look at the day-by-day data again, and
然后进行符号检验 需要返回查看每天的具体数据
I'll count the number of days where the click through rate is higher in
对实验组点击率较高的天数
the experiment group.
进行计数
I've checked the days where this is true, and
检查后发现 在实验运行的 14 天里
it's turned out to be the case for 9 out of 14 days.
实验组点击率高于对照组的有 9 天
Putting 9 and 14 into the sign test calculator, and
把 9 和 14 填入符号检验计算器里
clicking Calculate Probabilities, I get that the two-tailed value is 0.4240.
点击"计算概率"后 得到的双尾 P 值为 0.4240
This is pretty likely, and
这表明可能性很大
it's definitely not significant at an alpha equals 0.05 level.
在 α 值为 0.05 时 显然不具有显著性
So the hypothesis test on the effect size showed statistically
因此 对于同一效应值而言 假设检验具有统计显著性
significant results, but the sign test didn't.
但是符号检验却没有
Why could this happen?
为什么产生这种检验结果？
Well, first off, the sign test has lower power than the effect size test,
首先 符号检验的效能低于效应值检验
which is frequently the case for nonparametric tests.
这种情况常见于非参数检验
That's the price you pay for not making any assumptions.
这就是不作任何假设的代价
So, this isn't necessarily a red flag, but it's worth digging deeper and
所以 虽然它不一定就是示警信号 但我们的确应当深入分析
seeing if we can figure out what's going on.
了解实验过程
I'll take a look again at which days showed a positive effect size.
然后再次计算得到积极成果的天数
It looks like it was Tuesday, Saturday, Sunday, Monday, Tuesday, Thursday,
从表格中可以看到 有周二、周六、周日、周一、周二、周四
Friday, Saturday, Sunday.
周五、周六和周日
Now these aren't necessarily strange results.
看起来并无异常
But one thing to notice is that all four weekend days were positive.
但是值得注意的是 周末的四天均获得积极成果
In fact, if you look at the click-through rate in the experiment
事实上 返回查看实验组周末的点击率
group on the weekends, it's much higher than the click-through rate on
发现远高于其他时间
any other day, even the other days that did show a positive change.
甚至也高于其他获得积极成果的时间
This suggests that maybe the change has a small effect or
这表示 更改措施在工作日内的成效可能不大或几乎没有
no effect during the week, but a larger effect on weekends.
但在周末却成效明显
I won't step through calculating the confidence interval for weekdays and
我不会分别逐步演示工作日及周末置信区间的计算过程
weekends separately, but if you do, these are the results you'll get.
不过如果你计算了 得到的结果应该是这样的
It looks like the weekdays don't have a statistically significant difference,
数据表明 工作日置信区间之差不具有统计显著性
but the weekends do for at least the difference of 0.036.
而周末则相反 置信区间差值至少约为 0.036
That's consistent with the hypothesis that the weekends have a large effect
这与周末成效明显而工作日没有影响
and the weekdays have no effect.
的假设一致
The signed test results are also consistent with this hypothesis.
符号检验的结果也符合以上假设
If there were no effect on weekdays,
如果工作日没有变化
you would expect half the weekdays to be positive, which is exactly what we see,
你会希望工作日中有一半时间获得积极成果 正如数据所示
and all the weekends to be positive, which again, is what we see.
而且周末均能获得积极成果 也正如数据所示
Now, there are two main questions to answer in deciding what recommendation
现在要决定对实验提出何种建议
to make for this experiment.
还需回答两个问题
The first is whether it's okay that only weekends seem to have improved,
首先 可以只让周末的点击率有所提高吗？
and the second is whether the magnitude of the change makes it worth launching.
第二 更改变更幅度是否能使实验推行具有价值？
Remember, the practical significance level was 0.01,
记住 实际显著性为 0.01
and the confidence interval for the overall effect included this boundary.
包含在整体效应的置信区间范围内
The weekend effect was stronger than the practical significance level, but
周末成效的置信区间高于实际显著性
you may want a bigger practical significance level for
你需要对仅影响周末的变更
a change that only affects weekends.
得到更高的实际显著性
Based on this, I would recommend not launching the experiment at this point.
因此 我建议当前不推行实验
Instead, I would dig deeper into why the change didn't affect weekday visitors.
但是 我会进一步研究 为什么更改措施不对工作日的访问用户产生影响
Once I understood that, I might have an idea for
找到原因后 我可能就知道
how to iterate on the change to help it affect more of the users.
该如何重新设计更改方案 从而影响更多用户
If not, then I'd talk to the decision makers about whether a change of this
如果未能找到原因 我会找决策者谈一谈
magnitude on weekend traffic is worth launching.
讨论对周日流量影响效果达到该种程度的更改方案是否值得推行